

## **Contact**

#### Phone

+92335-0392664

#### **Email**

<u>hamiz786ak@gmail.com</u>

#### **Address**

Gulberg, Karachi

## Links

#### linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hamiz-ahmed 778729245/

#### **My Portfolio**

https://hamyz-portfolio.netlify.app/

## **Skills**

- Python (Programming Language)
- JavaScript
- Java
- HTML5 and CSS
- React
- UI/UX
- SEO / Content Writing
- MySQL
- Project Management
- Figma (Software)
- Adobe Illustrator
- Problem Solving
- · Visual Design

# Language

#### **English**

# **Hamiz** Ahmed

## Developer and Designer

Computer Scientist to be, Recently studying bachelors of computer science from Iqra University also have some certifications from expertise like Udemy and Coursera, willing to learn more. I am a highly skilled and experienced programmer, developer, and graphic designer with a passion for creating innovative and user-friendly products. I have a strong understanding of both the technical and creative aspects of design, and I am able to translate my ideas into code that is both efficient and elegant.

## **Education**

## O Iqra University (Official)

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

Oct, 2020 - May, 2024

Currently Enrolled in Iqra University, doing bachelor's in Computer Science (BSCS)

# **Experience**

### Freelancer Designer and Developer

Upwork I Karachi

#### Mar, 2023 - Present

- Versatile skill set in design and development.
- Delivers high-quality design solutions and tailored technical implementations.
- Consistently exceeds client expectations.

# Back-End Engineering Virtual Experience Program (Remote-Internship)

Lyft I San Francisco, California, United States

#### Jun, 2023 - Present

- Software Architecture
- · Refactoring,
- Unit Testing
- Test-Driven Development

# Agile Methodology Virtual Experience Program (Remote-Internship)

Cognizant I Teaneck, New Jersey, United States

#### April, 2023 - July, 2023

- Project Management
- · Role Assignments and Ceremonies.

## Certification

### Front-End Development

Coursera

May, 2022 - Nov, 2022

The course engaged in Learning of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for dynamic web interfaces. Gain skills in responsive design, user experience, and industry best practices. Prepare for a career in this evolving field through hands-on projects.

### Basics of UI / UX

Great Learning

Mar, 2023 - May, 2023

Learned the fundamentals of user interface (UI) and user experience (UX) design. Gain practical knowledge in creating intuitive and engaging digital experiences.